<listEvent>
               <event ana="#event" when="1588-08-08">
                  <label>Spanish Armada, Defeat of</label>
                  <note ana="#description">
                     <p> A battle between the Spanish and English naval armies near Gravelines,
                        France in the English Channel. Though the Spanish fleet only lost 4 of its
                        130 ships during the battle, over 50 ships were lost in retreat. The defeat
                        marked the beginning of the end of Spanish dominance in Europe. </p>
                  </note>
                  <bibl>
                     <ptr target="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_Armada"/>
                  </bibl>
               </event>
               <event ana="#event" when="1870">
                  <label>First Vatican Council, 1869-70</label>
                  <note ana="#description">
                     <p> The Vatican council of <date when="1870">1870</date>, at which
                        the dotrine of Papal infallibility was established. </p>
                  </note>
                  <bibl>
                     <ptr target="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_Vatican_Council"/>
                  </bibl>
               </event>
               <event ana="#event" when="1867-11-03">
                  <label>Mentana, Battle of</label>
                  <note ana="#description">
                     <p> French and Papal armies numbering 9000 defeat Garibaldi's forces
                        numbering 4000. </p>
                  </note>
               </event>
               <event ana="#event">
                  <label>Insurrection in Candia</label>
                  <note ana="description">
                     <p> The largest of series of Cretan Christian uprisings against the Ottoman
                        Empire that last from <date>1866-1869</date>. </p>
                  </note>
               </event>
               <event ana="#event" when="1862-08-29">
                  <label>Battle of Aspromonte</label>
                  <note ana="#description">
                     <p> A encounter that occured on <date when="1862-08-29">August 29,
                            1862</date> in southern Italy between the Italian government and the
                        Italian Unificationists. The Unificationist leader, Garibaldi, was wounded
                        and taken prisoner during the battle. </p>
                  </note>
                  <bibl>
                     <ptr target="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Aspromonte"/>
                  </bibl>
               </event>
               <event ana="#event">
                  <label>English Civil War</label>
                  <note ana="#description">
                     <p> A series of battles between Parliamentarians and Royalists. The civil
                        war resulted in the execution of King Charles I and the establishment of the
                        Commonwealth of England. </p>
                  </note>
                  <bibl>
                     <ptr target="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_Civil_War"/>
                  </bibl>
               </event>
               <event ana="#event">
                  <label>Battle of Trebbia</label>
                  <note ana="#description">
                     <p> A battle fought by the Trebbia river in northern Italy between the
                        French and the Austrians and Russians. Both sides lost 6,000 soldiers, but
                        the Austro-Russian army was victorious. </p>
                  </note>
                  <bibl>
                     <ptr target="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_the_Trebia"/>
                  </bibl>
               </event>
               <event ana="#event" when="1567-06-15">
                  <label>Carberry Hill, Battle of</label>
                  <note ana="#description">
                     <p> Supporters of Mary, Queen of Scotland and her new husband, James
                        Hepburn, Earl of Bothwell, uprise against Queen Elizabeth I a few miles east
                        of Ediburgh, Scotland. Mary I is captured, imprisoned in Loch Leven Castle,
                        and later executed. </p>
                  </note>
               </event>
               <event ana="#event">
                  <label>St. Bartholomew's Day Massacre</label>
                  <note ana="#description">
                     <p> A wave of targeted assassinations and subsequent Roman Catholic mob
                        violence against the Huguenots. The events began on the <date when="1572-08-23">23 August 1572</date>, the eve of St.
                        Bartholomew's feast day, with murders ordered by Charles IX of France. The
                        massacres lasted several weeks, and spread throughout Paris and then to
                        other urban centers and the country side. </p>
                  </note>
                  <bibl>
                     <ptr target="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St._Bartholomew%27s_Day_massacre"/>
                  </bibl>
               </event>
               <event ana="#event">
                  <label>Anthesteria</label>
                  <note ana="#description">
                     <p> One of four Athenian festivals honoring Dionysus. </p>
                  </note>
                  <bibl>
                     <ptr target="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anthesteria"/>
                  </bibl>
               </event>
            </listEvent>